<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 17:43:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ryanlmahan.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CSS for the scared web developer</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/css-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:26:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/css-intro/</guid><description>As a fledgling web developer, I loathed having to use CSS, usually copying and pasting layouts, snippets, and using frameworks to create my components for me. I noticed that others in my department were having the same struggles and set out to learn, then share, how to write effective CSS. This presentation was the culmination of that effort, and has reshaped how many in my department view writing their own CSS.</description></item><item><title>Effectively Giving and Receiving Feedback</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/feedback/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:23:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/feedback/</guid><description>Given to various groups at Optum before our peer feedback rounds. This presentation guides feedback givers to a well-crafted message to ensure proper communication of areas for improvement. Feedback receivers are given tips on staying constructive, guiding self-reflection, and how to encourage others to give feedback more often. A main theme throughout the presentation is that feedback is gift worth giving, getting, and working together to properly share.</description></item><item><title>Police Data Trust</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/police-data-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:10:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/police-data-trust/</guid><description> Github
Police Data Trust is being created to act as a unified search experience across multiple non-profit police misconduct tracking organizations in order to increase visibility of repeat offenders across municipalities. The project uses Next.js, Python, Flask, and PostgresQL. I contribute full stack, developing the user authentication, session management, and other user managment functionality.</description></item><item><title>Developing Reusable React Libraries</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/react-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 1970 21:56:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/react-libraries/</guid><description>Given to my department in coordination with a larger push for developing reusable resources, this presentation fills a knowledge gap of setting up, developing, and publishing NPM packages designed for react applications. A combination of NPM package mechanics and design paradigms for creating maintainable and highly configurable libraries, this presentation helped my department increase code reusability. Alongside this presenation, I developed an internal react hooks library based off of a template repository that would enable other developers to start on their library ideas without having to learn the intracacies of build tools.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Node and Express</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/node-intro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:39:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/presentations/node-intro/</guid><description>Targeted for web developers with 1-3 years of experience in another framework, this presentation highlights the basic tools provided by Node.js and the Express framework. It covers the basic mechanics of route management, middleware, the request and response objects. Compares functional endpoint organization with object oriented practices, using typescript over javascript, and examples from enterprise backend services I have built.</description></item><item><title>Can Copilot pass a coding interview?</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/blog/copilotinterview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 17:43:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/blog/copilotinterview/</guid><description>Github Copilot is a natural language model built on OpenAI Codex that suggests code snippets based on existing comments and code. With Copilot, programmers write descriptive comments and function names and Copilot writes the rest. This is hilariously similar to the usual coding interview, which consists of a prompt and a template for a human to fill in with code. What if we replaced the human interviewee with Copilot? Would it generate good enough code to get a job?</description></item><item><title>How does React v18's concurrency improve performance?</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/blog/reactconcurrency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 18:27:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/blog/reactconcurrency/</guid><description>The React team has implemented concurrency on a single threaded V8 execution context. How does increased concurrency help when you only have one thread? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how Operating Systems developers were able to increase the performance of their hardware through the CPU scheduler.
First, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the React team&amp;rsquo;s writeup on their concurrency feature, or their more recent React v18 updates you should. They explain how they implemented it and how to use it.</description></item><item><title>BallotDropMA</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/ballot-drop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 17:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/ballot-drop/</guid><description>API Github
Github
A website built to help MA residents find their closest ballot drop box. I scraped the Secretary of State's website to get the data, then hosted it in a MongoDB Atlas instance. The backend is something I'm particularly proud of, generic controllers and services work by dependency inversion of the Mongoose Models. The API and Webapp were hosted on Azure from September to December 2020.</description></item><item><title>Fore River Twitter Bot</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/fore-river/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 16:39:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/fore-river/</guid><description>Github
A twitter bot for posting when the Route 3A bridge in Fore River opens. Written using Python and hosted on a raspberry pi on my home network. Follow us on twitter.</description></item><item><title>WTFUmass</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/wtfumass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 16:30:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/wtfumass/</guid><description>Github
"What to Fix, UMass" was a site developed in my senior year at UMass. As Speaker of the Undergraduate Senate I sought to create a method for students to provide feedback to the instution and vote on topics they'd like to see their representatives focus on. WTFUMass used Vue, Node, and MongoDB. I used firebase for authentication methods, and vueitfy's component library.</description></item><item><title>Hi, I'm Ryan Mahan</title><link>https://ryanlmahan.com/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/home/</guid><description>Software Engineer, Student, Dog Dad</description></item></channel></rss>