<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on </title>
    <link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 16:31:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Data Trust</title>
      <link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/police-data-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 21:10:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/police-data-trust/</guid>
      <description>Github
 Police Data Trust is being created to act as a unified search experience across multiple non-profit police misconduct tracking organizations in order to increase visibility of repeat offenders across municipalities. The project uses Next.js, Python, Flask, and PostgresQL. I contribute full stack, developing the user authentication, session management, and other user managment functionality. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BallotDropMA</title>
      <link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/ballot-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 17:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/ballot-drop/</guid>
      <description>API Github
Github
 A website built to help MA residents find their closest ballot drop box. I scraped the Secretary of State&#39;s website to get the data, then hosted it in a MongoDB Atlas instance. The backend is something I&#39;m particularly proud of, generic controllers and services work by dependency inversion of the Mongoose Models. The API and Webapp were hosted on Azure from September to December 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fore River Twitter Bot</title>
      <link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/fore-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 16:39:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/fore-river/</guid>
      <description>Github
 A twitter bot for posting when the Route 3A bridge in Fore River opens. Written using Python and hosted on a raspberry pi on my home network. Follow us on twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTFUmass</title>
      <link>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/wtfumass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 16:30:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanlmahan.com/projects/wtfumass/</guid>
      <description>Github
 &#34;What to Fix, UMass&#34; was a site developed in my senior year at UMass. As Speaker of the Undergraduate Senate I sought to create a method for students to provide feedback to the instution and vote on topics they&#39;d like to see their representatives focus on. WTFUMass used Vue, Node, and MongoDB. I used firebase for authentication methods, and vueitfy&#39;s component library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>